## James E Harris II

jameseharrisii@gmail.com|

About me: With 15 years of experience as an over-the-road trucker, I have a proven track record of success in the transportation industry. As an owner-operator, I've gained valuable experience in managing my own business and maintaining my vehicle. My focus on fuel efficiency through techniques like reducing engine RPMs has resulted in a 15% reduction in fuel consumption compared to the industry average

## **Employment history**

Time Management App, Back-end developer Mar 2024 - April 2024

Stack: [MongoDB, Mongoose, AWS\_practitioner, React, JavaScript]

Worked on a team of 4, alongside 2 engineers (Front-end and Back-end), a PM and a designer • Built a time management app entire Back-end database schema that controls product's functionality. Referrals per week initially increased by 100%, and then A/B tested (e.g. tweaked app) to optimize further and reach a 350% increase • Built and contributed to a number of microservices including writing tests and setting up CI pipelines • Delivered training on JavaScript engineering team, in preparation of moving our codebase over • Involved in aspects of building the business, from product design to performance marketing.

Rock The Vote, Junior Full-stack Engineer Jan 2024 - Mar 2024

Stack: [React, JavaScript, Express, NodeJs, Google Cloud

React, JavaScript, GCP • Worked on a 2-month project to allow customers to track their home-sale. Followed a sprint process, collaborated with user research and design teams to ensure we were solving the biggest problems • Built internal tools to automate tasks, worked closely with the sales team to understand their problems. Saved an estimated 10 hours per week per person • Built data-processing pipelines in JavaScript with Elasticsearch so we could build a local-price-tracker that used live data from Zoopla and the Land Registry • Consistently ranked as a 'star performer' within the engineering team.

## Education

V-school Coding\_bootcamp – Web Development Certification Nov 2022 – Mar 2024